<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://softwareobservatorium.github.io/blog</id>
    <title>LASSO Blog</title>
    <updated>2025-02-17T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://softwareobservatorium.github.io/blog"/>
    <subtitle>LASSO Blog</subtitle>
    <icon>https://softwareobservatorium.github.io/img/favicon.ico</icon>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[(WIP) Arena Test Driver for Python Available]]></title>
        <id>https://softwareobservatorium.github.io/blog/arena-python</id>
        <link href="https://softwareobservatorium.github.io/blog/arena-python"/>
        <updated>2025-02-17T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We're excited to share that our efforts to support Python in the LASSO platform are gaining momentum! A first version of the arena test driver for Python is now available on GitHub, accessible at https://github.com/SoftwareObservatorium/arena-python.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We're excited to share that our efforts to support Python in the LASSO platform are gaining momentum! A first version of the arena test driver for Python is now available on GitHub, accessible at <a href="https://github.com/SoftwareObservatorium/arena-python" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://github.com/SoftwareObservatorium/arena-python</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Key Features</strong></p>
<p>Our current development includes support for essential data structures used in LASSO:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>LQL</strong>: Our Lasso Query Language (LQL) implementation allows you to represent interfaces in a concise and readable manner.</li>
<li><strong>SSN</strong>: Sequence sheet notation is also supported, providing a convenient way to work with biological sequences.</li>
<li><strong>Stimulus Response Matrices</strong>: We've integrated the use of pandas DataFrames to create and manipulate these matrices.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What's Next</strong></p>
<p>We're working on integrating our Python support into the LASSO platform, specifically the LSL pipeline language. This will enable you to leverage the full power of LASSO in your Python workflows.</p>
<p><strong>Explore Our Examples</strong></p>
<p>Get hands-on experience with our Python implementation using Jupyter Notebooks:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/SoftwareObservatorium/arena-python/tree/main/notebooks" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://github.com/SoftwareObservatorium/arena-python/tree/main/notebooks</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Additionally, you can explore the system tests for the arena API in our GitHub repository:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/SoftwareObservarium/arena-python/tree/main/tests" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://github.com/SoftwareObservatorium/arena-python/tree/main/tests</a></li>
</ul>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Marcus Kessel</name>
            <uri>https://www.wim.uni-mannheim.de/atkinson/team/dr-marcus-kessel/</uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing the New Project Website!]]></title>
        <id>https://softwareobservatorium.github.io/blog/new-project-website</id>
        <link href="https://softwareobservatorium.github.io/blog/new-project-website"/>
        <updated>2025-02-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exciting news, everyone! We are thrilled to announce the launch of the brand new website for LASSO, the Large-Scale Software Observatorium for the Dynamic Selection, Analysis and Comparison of Software.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Exciting news, everyone! We are thrilled to announce the launch of the brand new website for LASSO, the Large-Scale Software Observatorium for the Dynamic Selection, Analysis and Comparison of Software.</p>
<p>The new website features:</p>
<ul>
<li>A clean and modern design: Easier to navigate and visually appealing.</li>
<li>Detailed project documentation: Get a comprehensive understanding of LASSO's features, functionality, and how to use it effectively.</li>
<li>A vibrant community section: Connect with other LASSO users, share your experiences, and contribute to the project's growth.</li>
</ul>
<p>Regular blog updates: Stay informed about the latest developments, news, and insights related to LASSO.</p>
<p>With the new website, we aim to:</p>
<ul>
<li>Make LASSO more accessible to a wider audience.</li>
<li>Foster a stronger sense of community around the project.</li>
<li>Encourage contributions and collaboration from developers and users alike.</li>
</ul>
<p>Explore everything LASSO has to offer. We encourage you to leave your feedback, ask questions, and join the growing community of LASSO users (<a href="https://softwareobservatorium.github.io/contact">Contact Us</a>).</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Marcus Kessel</name>
            <uri>https://www.wim.uni-mannheim.de/atkinson/team/dr-marcus-kessel/</uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>